Guide to the New-York Historical Society Collection of Stereographs 1850-1964 (Bulk 1860-1900) PR 65
New-York Historical Society
- Geographic, 1850-1964
  - Europe, Italy--Rome, [1860-1910] (Box 68)
    Identifier:PR-065-0737
    Rome: Roman sites including the Colosseum, and the Forum; Trevi fountain; sculpture churches, including St. Peter's Basilica; views at the Vatican, including the Vatican Library, and Pope Pius X.
    65 items
  - Europe, Luxembourg, [1865] (Box 69)
    Identifier:PR-065-0738
    Unidentified palace in Luxembourg.
  - Europe, Malta, [1870] (Box 69)
    Identifier:PR-065-0739
    A quay in Malta.
  - Europe, Monaco, [1870-1900] (Box 69)
    Identifier:PR-065-0740
    Monaco: sunken gardens; buildings on cliff; interior views of the Casino.
  - Europe, Netherlands, [1870-1900] (Box 69)
    Identifier:PR-065-0741
    Netherlands: canals, windmills, interior of ornate room; interior of a building once visited (?) by Peter the Great.
  - Europe, Norway, [1896-1910] (Box 69)
    Identifier:PR-065-0742
    Norway: fish market in Bern; mountain road; a waterfall; Naerofjord; English church in Christiania.
  - Europe, Poland, [1900] (Box 69)
    Identifier:PR-065-0743
    Poland: market at Warsaw; Victory monument at Leipzig.
  - Europe, Russia, [1880-1920] (Box 69)
    Identifier:PR-065-0744
    Russia: rural scenery; a Russian cruiser; views in Moscow including the Kremlin, bridges, churches, coach with Czar Nicholas during his coronation; portrait of the royal family; Czar Nicholas and his wife (wax figures?); Petersburg: Winter Palace, St. Michael's Palace.
  - Europe, Scotland, [1860-1870] (Box 69)
    Identifier:PR-065-0745
    Scotland: Aberdeen; Abbotsford, home of Sir Walter Scott, including interiors; Balmoral Castle; cattle in field outside Callender; views on the Clyde; Drummond Castle; Edinburgh; ruins of Elgin Cathedral; interiors of Glasgow Cathedral, Glasgow necropolis; Haddon Hall; ruins at Holyrood, and at Jedburgh Abbey; scenery in the Trossachs; Melrose Abbey; the Great Forth Bridge; Robert Burn's cottage; Sandringham, including portrait of 4 men reading a newspaper; Stirling Castle and Wallace Monument.
  - Europe, Spain, [1880] (Box 69)
    Identifier:PR-065-0746
    Spain: interior of a chapel at the Alhambra; view at Tarragona.
  - Europe, Sweden, [1896-1910] (Box 69)
    Identifier:PR-065-0747
    Sweden: Royal Palace including interior; canal of Gothenburg; group going to church; woman milking cow.
  - Europe, Switzerland, [1860-1910] (Box 69)
    Identifier:PR-065-0748
    Switzerland: mountains, mountaineers, glaciers, rivers and bridges, railroads, tourists, valleys and villages, lakes; views in Bern, Lucerne, Zurich and other locations, including view on a glacier with photographer's tent.
  - Europe, Wales, [1860-1870] (Box 69)
    Identifier:PR-065-0749
    Wales: Caswell Bay; ruins at Tintern Abbey; Harlech Castle; women in tradition costume; general view of Dolgelly and Cader Idris; the Ller Valley.
  - Europe, unknown, [1850-1875] (Box 69)
    Identifier:PR-065-0750
    Views at unidentified European locations, including rural scenery, houses, churches, groups photographed out of doors.
  - Africa, Egypt, [1858-1900] (Box 69)
    Identifier:PR-065-0751
    Egypt: Cleopatra's Needle, Alexandria; Cairo: streets, women grinding corn, Bedouin and camel, ostrich farm, a mosque; Gizeh: the pyramids and the Sphinx; Karnak: temples and columns; Lbsamboul, great temple, later the site of the Aswan dam; government corn stores at Luxor; Philae: looking toward first cataract, gate, mosque; pyramid at Sakhara; palace at Thebes.
  - Africa, South Africa, [1880-1900] (Box 70)
    Identifier:PR-065-0752
    South Africa: saw mill tram track through glade with ferns and trees; Boer War views, including camps, men shouting from behind redoubts, wounded soldiers, Gen. de la Rey's army on the move, Cronje's men in prison camp, Col. Porter's men ready for Boer cavalry charge.
  - Asia, China, [1860-1905] (Box 70)
    Identifier:PR-065-0753
    China: Beijing: public well, Buddhist temple, U.S. Infantry line along road in front of Sacred Gate; Canton: West Gate, view from the walls, pagoda, portrait of Tseang Keun, general of Canton army, view on the parade ground, crowds on canal road; Port Arthur: Japanese artillery being shot into Port Arthur, Japanese soldiers in trenches, Japanese dead in trench, Russian dead; Tientsin: Sikhs firing British artillery into the city, and a general view of the city after bombardment and fire.
  - Asia, Holy Land, [1860-1905] (Box 70)
    Identifier:PR-065-0754
    Holy Land including Palestine (Israel), Lebanon, and Syria: Bethlehem; tomb of Rachel; Bethany; Cana in Galilee; Jerusalem: general views, the Wailing Wall, Garden of Gesthemane, "David's Judgement seat," Mount of Olives, pool of Gihon, tombs of Abraham and the Patriarchs, street scenes, portrait of a Jew of Jerusalem; wilderness of Engedi; Mount Carmel; Mount Tabor; Jenin; Jezreel; mosque at Hebron; valley of Kedron; Nazareth from the west; ruins of Church of St. John in Samaria; Jacob's well; Sharon; Shechem; Shiloh; Sinai: valley, palms, convent, and portrait of abbot and monks, Wady Mukatteb, with specimen of Semitic writing; travelers on camels; fountain of Jericho; site of Capernaum, ruins of synagogue; Rasheiya, looking towards Lebanon; Cedars of Lebanon; sheik's house, Mt. Lebanon; Beirut, including interior of home; interior of hotel in Damascus; Caesarea Philippi; Tiberias; Gorge of Brook Cherith and Elijah Convent.
  - Asia, India, 1899-1903 (Box 70)
    Identifier:PR-065-0755
    India: interior of Adhesar Temple, and Vimala Sah at Mt. Abu; road lined with poplars, Kashmir; Taj Mahal; interior of Great Durbar, palace of H.H. the Maharaja of Gwalior; elephants in the Durbar procession; royal cenotaphs, Chitor; Moslems at prayer, Jumma Musjib.
  - Asia, Japan, [1896-1905] (Box 70)
    Identifier:PR-065-0756
    Japan: gardens; tea plantations; Mt. Fuji, and view from the mountain; Sasuka Temple, Tokyo; fishermen at Yokohama; bronze Buddha, Kamakura; geishas serving a meal; portrait of Count Okuma and interior of his home; general view of Kobe; street scene in Osaka; women in a rickshaw in Kyoto.
  - Asia, Philippines, [1900] (Box 70)
    Identifier:PR-065-0757
    Philippines: Igorots; Manila: street scene, landing cattle from a boat, fish market, the harbor, tents on the parade ground.
  - Asia, Sri Lanka, 1903 (Box 70)
    Identifier:PR-065-0758
    Sri Lanka: sunset an beach, palm tree silhouetted.
  - Asia, Turkey, [1860s] (Box 70)
    Identifier:PR-065-0759
    Turkey: views in Istanbul (Constantinople): Palace of the Sultan at Dalma Batchi; view from the Seraskier Tower showing the golden horn and Mosque of Sultan Suleyman; new palace and Bosphorus from the west.
- Subjects, 1860-1920
  Subject Series: This series is arranged by subject or topic. Items are arranged into groups, and each group has an Identifier, or unique number. The Identifier can be found within the group's Scope and Contents note. Many of the items arranged by subject are of unknown location. Other subjects have known locations, but depict substantial and important subjects, such as the Civil War or the Spanish American War. Some of the items form published series, such as the Powell and Wheeler expeditions in the American West. It may be necessary to search the Geographic Series for subjects that are also represented in the Subject Series. For instance, there is a subject group titled Indians of North America, but there are additional views of Native American Indians dispersed throughout the Geographic Series.
  Civil War stereographs have been digitized and are available online via New York Heritage.
  - Subjects--African Americans, [1860-1900] (Box 70)
    Identifier:PR-065-0760
    African Americans: working in cotton, including picking cotton, cleaning cotton, and people with large baskets of cotton on their heads; group by plantation cabin; European American reading book to group of men and boys; family groups pictured in front of their homes; men with ox carts; children with watermelon; boy with rooster; boy with banjo singing; couple walking; two boys and bicycle wheel.
  - Subjects--Agriculture, [1860-1901] (Box 70)
    Identifier:PR-065-0761
    Agricultural views and rural scenes: farms, including farm houses and yards, cattle, sheep, women feeding yard of chickens, children feeding a horse, haying, including views in the winter, hop pickers, a peddler at a farm house, group in decorated boat for harvest festival, a log cabin, agricultural implements at unidentified fair; includes sentimental views.
  - Subjects--Agriculture, Maple sugar, [1880-1910] (Box 70)
    Identifier:PR-065-0762
    Maple sugaring: gathering syrup from trees, boiling it down, and group gathered for a "sugar feast"
  - Subjects--Animals, undated (Box 71)
    Identifier:PR-065-0763
    Animals: trained bear; buffalo: on a city street, herd of buffalo, and buffalo skulls; girl with cat and doll; dogs, including a dog in a hat, and with a cigar in his mouth; a fox; a frog; goats: children playing with a goat, child with goat cart; gorilla; monkeys in a bar scene, some with pipes, monkeys with musical instruments, monkeys in a domestic scene; birds: taxidermied arrangements of birds, duck and other game birds hanging from string, bittern, bird of paradise, quails, buzzards, grouse or prairie chicken; two examples of coral.
  - Subjects--Art, [1870-1895] (Box 71)
    Identifier:PR-065-0764
    Art work: stack of five dollar bills; set of jewelry present to Mrs. Gen. Grant by Brown and Spaulding; lithograph depicting the George Washington and the Cherry Tree story; depiction of the first mass said in St. Augustine; Diana and Nymphs; Phyrne before the tribunal; Nymphs discover Cupid practicing his art; Fall of Babylon; Reprimanded (Piccou); Perry's victory on Lake Erie; lithograph depicting various values of Odd Fellowships; still life of household equipment, swords, a gun.
  - Subjects--Astronomy, [1859-1891] (Box 71)
    Identifier:PR-065-0765
    Views of the moon, most taken when full, including views made by H. Draper and L. M. Rutherford.
  - Subjects--Automobiles, [1910] (Box 71)
    Identifier:PR-065-0766
    Automobiles: race cars, one shown racing past the grandstands.
  - Subjects--Botany, [1860-1901] (Box 71)
    Identifier:PR-065-0767
    Botany: plants, flowers and vegetables, many hand-colored; floral arrangements, interior views of conservatories, gardens, a parsnip sculpted into the face of a man; arrangements made of leaf skeletons.
  - Subjects--Bridges, [1870] (Box 71)
    Identifier:PR-065-0768
    Bridges: unidentified covered bridge; Wabashaw St. bridge.
  - Subjects--Circuses and shows, [1890] (Box 71)
    Identifier:PR-065-0769
    Man on horseback next to elephant and circus tent.
  - Subjects--Circuses and shows--Buffalo Bill's Wild West Show, [1880-1910] (Box 71)
    Identifier:PR-065-0770
    Buffalo Bill's Wild West Show: William Cody with rifle, holding loving cup, and with men presenting floral tribute; "Miss Hicock" (Calamity Jane?) on horseback; Indians on horseback waiting for cue; Indian children, including a girl Sha Sha o pogi and a child on a pony; Bronco Charlie, dude cowboy; performers riding horses in a ring; view of men in Wyoming, possibly including Bill Cody or associates of him.
  - Subjects--Civil War, [1863-1890] (Box 71)
    Identifier:PR-065-0771
    Civil War: painting of a battle; field telegraph station.
  - Subjects--Civil War--African Americans, [1863-1880] (Box 71)
    Identifier:PR-065-0772
    African Americans: "contrabands" in a Union camp; Men, women and children in front of a building; family in a wagon coming into Union lines.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Camp Life, [1861-1865] (Box 71)
    Identifier:PR-065-0773
    Civil War camp life: general views of camps, including tents, forts, rough buildings; men eating, reading relaxing, playing, washing, arrayed in formation, and with horses; includes African Americans; one view shows man with wife and child in camp.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Dead, 1861-1865 (Box 71)
    Identifier:PR-065-0774
    Civil War dead: embalmer and corpse; unidentified Confederate casualty; grave of Union prisoners; members of a South Carolina regiment laid out for burial; an embalming building; African American soldier hanging from the gallows after his execution for attempted rape.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Hospitals, 1862-1865 (Box 71)
    Identifier:PR-065-0775
    Hospitals: Frank L. Keyes, at home recuperating; Sanitary commission wagons and tents.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Navy, [1861-1865] (Box 72)
    Identifier:PR-065-0776
    Civil War, navy: ships, including monitor class ships, gunboats, rams and frigates; group portraits of sailors and officers on deck; includes both Confederate and Union ships.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Portraits, Civilians, 1862-1886 (Box 72)
    Identifier:PR-065-0777
    Portraits of civilians: Harper's Weekly artist; Godfor, a "battlefield vulture"; Jim Kerrigan, "The mollie squealer"; Major Pinkerton, and others, including Lincoln.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Portraits, Lincoln, before 1865 (Box 72)
    Identifier:PR-065-0778
    Portraits of Lincoln; studio portraits, and in camps, including a view of Gen. McClellan at Antietam; most are copy prints.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Portraits, Officers, [1861-1865] (Box 72)
    Identifier:PR-065-0779
    Portraits of officers, including studio portraits and men shown in the field: Anderson, Bates, Butler, Corcoran, Crawford, Custer, Custer with Lt. J.B. Washington, a Confederate prisoner who was his classmate at West Point; Dix, Duryea, Farragut, Ferroro, Gordon, Grant, Hancock, Kearney, McClellan, Marcy, Moseby, Ord, Pleasonton, Patrick, Robertson, Rogers, Sherman, Smith, Strang, Sweeney, Thomas, Wheeler, Worden and others; some are Confederate officers; one view of Custer shows him with his dog.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Portraits, Soldiers, [1861-1865] (Box 72)
    Identifier:PR-065-0780
    Portraits of soldiers: Duryea's Zouaves and other groups standing in formation; men in camp; John Burns, the hero of Gettysburg; man sitting on case of hard tack; orderly with horse; men in trenches; men in a sally port by a draw bridge; group at Mr. Foller's farm.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Railroads, [1861-1865] (Box 72)
    Identifier:PR-065-0781
    Railroads: railroads that have been destroyed, including a railroad bridge; soldiers in front of a Baltimore and Ohio relay house.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Alabama, [1864] (Box 72)
    Identifier:PR-065-0782
    Fort Morgan, Alabama, after Farragut's bombardment.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Washington, D.C., [1861-1865] (Box 72)
    Identifier:PR-065-0783
    Washington, D.C. and vicinity: Gen. McClellan's HQ; views on the Potomac; Grand Review of returning soldiers, showing men on parade, and the reviewing stand with dignitaries.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Florida, [1861-1865] (Box 72)
    Identifier:PR-065-0784
    Florida: Signal tower near Jacksonville; Fort Marion, St. Augustine.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Georgia, [1862-1865] (Box 72)
    Identifier:PR-065-0785
    Georgia: Fort McAllister and Fort Pulaski, including interiors of the fort, artillery pieces, trenches.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Georgia, Atlanta, [1861-1865] (Box 72)
    Identifier:PR-065-0786
    Atlanta and vicinity: street views, railroad yards and depot; place where Gen. McPherson was killed; rebel fort north of the city; railroad outside the city that was torn up by Union forces; Potter house, damaged by Union fire; soldiers at picket station outside Atlanta.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Maryland, 1861-1864 (Box 72)
    Identifier:PR-065-0787
    Maryland: soldiers seated above the Patapsco bridge outside Baltimore; ruins of Gen. M. Blair's home; crew of gun boat practicing; Sharpsburg: street, Lutheran church damaged by fire; pontoon bridge across the Potomac at Berlin, and ruins of bridge that it replaced.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Maryland, Antietam, 1862 (Box 73)
    Identifier:PR-065-0788
    Battlefield at Antietam Maryland: dead lying in the field, and being buried; soldiers on the field, standing beneath trees; Tunker church; ruins of Mumma's house; Gen. Hooker's headquarters; Gen. Caldwell and staff; picnic party at Antietam bridge; Smith's barn, used as a hospital and straw huts nearby; signal tower on Elk Mt.; crowd gathered for Memorial Day at Antietam battlefield.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Mississippi, 1864 (Box 73)
    Identifier:PR-065-0789
    The levee at Vicksburg, lined with steamboats.
  - Subjects--Civil War--New York, [1861-1865] (Box 73)
    Identifier:PR-065-0790
    Parades on Broadway in New York, and barracks in City Hall Park.
  - Subjects--Civil War--New York, Union Square Rally, 1861 (Box 73)
    Identifier:PR-065-0791
    Great union Meeting, Union Square, New York April 20, 1861: crowds filling the park and surrounding streets, and lining the roofs of nearby buildings, with flags flying overhead.
  - Subjects--Civil War--North Carolina, [1861-1865] (Box 73)
    Identifier:PR-065-0792
    North Carolina: English Armstrong gun in Fort Fisher, N.C.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Pennsylvania, Gettysburg, 1863 (Box 73)
    Identifier:PR-065-0793
    Gettysburg: breastworks, fences, woods and the battlefield; dead on the battlefield; Confederate prisoners standing by breastwork; Round Top; Sugar Loaf Mountain; African Americans with a donkey: "all the livestock on Mr. Gill's plantation"; Lee's headquarters; Gen. Meade's headquarters; gate to the cemetery; John L. Burns' cottage; "Farmers' Inn and hotel, Emmittsburg, where our special artist was captured, July 5th, 1863"; home of James Gettys, founder of Gettysburg.
    60 items
  - Subjects--Civil War--South Carolina, [1861-1865] (Box 73)
    Identifier:PR-065-0794
    South Carolina: forts, including Fort Walker on Port Royal, Fort Wagner, Fort Chatfield, Fort Marshall, Fort Putnam, and fortifications, possibly on Hilton Head showing interiors of the forts, soldiers on guard and with artillery; battery of "Quaker guns"; ordnance yard on Morris Island; Smith's plantation scenes, including group of slaves in front of slave quarters, preparing cotton for the gin.
  - Subjects--Civil War--South Carolina, Beaufort, [1861-1865] (Box 73)
    Identifier:PR-065-0795
    Beaufort, S.C.: houses, some used as officers quarters, or military headquarters; streets; soldiers cemetery; 2nd U.S. Artillery, Colored with guns and tents; hospitals; boat landing; signal station, men on horseback below; store and post office; room decorated for ball; issuing stores to a group of Afican American people.
  - Subjects--Civil War--South Carolina, Charleston, [1864-1865] (Box 73)
    Identifier:PR-065-0796
    Charleston: Confederate batteries in the city; destruction caused by the Union shelling; churches, markets, Institute Hall; commercial wharf and battery; Mills House; club house at the race course; tomb of J.C. Calhoun; O'Connor House where Union officers were confined under fire.
  - Subjects--Civil War--South Carolina, Fort Moultrie, [1861-1867] (Box 73)
    Identifier:PR-065-0797
    Fort Moultrie, Charleston Harbor, S.C.: view of interior of the fort, showing guns, the sallyport, cannonballs in stacks, looking out toward beach of Sullivan's Island.
  - Subjects--Civil War--South Carolina, Fort Sumter, [1861-1865] (Box 73)
    Identifier:PR-065-0798
    Fort Sumter: general view of the fort, and interior view in 1861, after Anderson evacuated; views of the fort after destruction and capture by Union forces, including the Union flag raising, April 14, 1865.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Tennessee, [1861-1865] (Box 74)
    Identifier:PR-065-0799
    Tennessee: views in Nashville; bridge over the Cumberland on the Louisville and Nashville R.R.; Knoxville R.R. depot at Chattanooga, group of rebel soldiers waiting transport north; Lookout Mountain; federal camp at Johnsonville.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Virginia, [1861-1865] (Box 74)
    Identifier:PR-065-0800
    Virginia: camp and artillery of the Army of the Potomac; Fort Brady; Fort Corcoran; Falls Church; Cobb's Hill: the signal corps, and African American teamsters; Cold Harbor, including views of Gen. Grant and Gen. Rawlins; Gen. Butler's Headquarters; Fort Sedgwick; Fort Totten; Dutch Gap, including African American pickets on duty; Sulphur Springs, hotel, officers of the 60th New York Volunteers; graves of Union dead south of Wilderness church; Cumberland landing; Captain's mess, African American children waiting table; Bealton; the Rappahannock, during the battle of Chancellorsville; church in Centreville used as hospital; camp at Centreville; Quaker guns; fugitive slave crossing the Rappahannock; Culpepper; Warrenton, including view of the courthouse; Catlett's station; Aquia Creek landing; Lacy house, Falmouth; ruins of bridge at Germania Ford; 18th century carriage; Bethel Church; bridges on the Pamunkey; Savage Station.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Virginia, Alexandria, [1861-1865] (Box 74)
    Identifier:PR-065-0801
    Alexandria, Virginia: bridge construction corps at work; interior of a barn; railroad yard, and slave pen; slave pen with soldier standing inside of it; Marshall house.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Virginia, Appomattox, [1865] (Box 74)
    Identifier:PR-065-0802
    Appomattox: pontoon bridge on the Appomattox River near Broadway Landing; house where General Lee signed the capitulation papers.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Virginia, Bull Run, [1861-1865] (Box 74)
    Identifier:PR-065-0803
    Bull Run: views on the battlefield at Bull Run including remains of the dead and graves, soldiers on horseback and Sudley's Ford and church, Robinson's House, ruins of houses, Beauregard's headquarters (later McDowell's), a monument, men lounging by tents at a picket's station; Sherman's battery on its return from Bull Run; bridge at Bull Run built by McDowell's engineers; T.H. O'Sullivan and photographers wagon; painting of the battle.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Virginia, Cedar Mountain, 1862 (Box 74)
    Identifier:PR-065-0804
    Cedar Mountain, Virginia: house, riddled with cannonballs; officers of the 10th Maine on the battlefield; dead horses; graves of Union soldiers; battery fording the Rappahannock; Culpepper courthouse, with group of Confederate prisoners.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Virginia, City Point, 1864-1865 (Box 74)
    Identifier:PR-065-0805
    City Point, Virginia, on the James River, supply point and headquarters of Union forces during the siege of Petersburg: wharves, sailing ships, barges, steamboats, General Grant's headquarters, portraits of General Grant, one with his wife and son, orderly with Grant's horse Cincinnati, Gen. Rawlins, wife and child, soldiers and winter quarters, soldiers serving out rations, army wagon going to Commissary, graves of soldiers near the hospital.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Virginia, Fair Oaks, 1862 (Box 74)
    Identifier:PR-065-0806
    Fair Oaks: frame house on battlefield used at a hospital; Professor Lowe observing the battle of Fair Oaks from his balloon; Gibson's battery of horse artillery; soldiers and artillery by frame house; redoubt on the front; soldiers in front of Quarles house; men and cannons at Fort Sumner, Fair Oaks.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Virginia, Fortress Monroe, [1863] (Box 74)
    Identifier:PR-065-0807
    Fort Monroe and vicinity: views of the fort, including fortifications and moat, a large artillery piece; group portraits of men in camp; tents in Camp Hamilton, bridge destroyed at Hampton, near Fortress Monroe; Zouaves at Camp Butler.
  - Subjects--Civil War--Virginia, Fredericksburg, 1863 (Box 74)
    Identifier:PR-065-0808